A Guide to the Administrative Files of the Virginia Dept. of Welfare, 1960-1978
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Administrative Files of the Virginia Dept. of Welfare, 1960-1978
The Library of Virginia
30671
5 cubic feet (5 Boxes)
Virginia Dept. of Welfare
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Virginia Dept. of Social Services on April 3, 1980.
Historical Information
On March 13, 1908, an act creating the Board of Charities and Corrections was passed by the General Assembly. The name of the board was changed to the Board of Public Welfare by the General Assembly on February 27, 1922, and the state government reorganization act of April 18, 1927, created the Department of Public Welfare. The General Assembly, on March 30, 1948, approved a reorganization of the state government that merged the Department of Public Welfare with the Department of Corrections to form the Department of Welfare and Institutions. This merger proved administratively unsatisfactory, so following several years of study, the General Assembly passed an act on March 9, 1974, separating the agencies to form the Department of Corrections and the Department of Welfare. On February 20, 1981, the General Assembly changed the name of the Department of Welfare to the Department of Social Services, effective July 1, 1982.
Scope and Content
Administrative Files, 1960-1978, include correspondence and subject files related to the Division of Field Services.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in original order.
Contents List
- Administrative files, 1960-1978.
  - General, 1977-1978. (Box 1)
  - Complaints, 1973-1977. (Box 1)
  - Consultants - Peat, Marwick and Mitchell, 1970. (Box 1)
  - Consultants - Systems Management Corp., 1971-1974. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Sen. Russell Long, 1972. (Box 1)
  - Field Operations, Div. of, 1976-1978. (Box 1)
  - General Welfare Division Reorganization - General, 1969-1972. (Box 1)
  - General Welfare Division Reorganization - General, 1973. (Box 1)
  - General Welfare Division Reorganization - Meetings, 1972. (Box 1)
  - General Welfare Division Reorganization - Charts, 1972-1973. (Box 1)
  - General Welfare Division Reorganization - Working papers, 1972. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - Management Study, 1970-1976. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - Manpower Planning Council, 1974-1976. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - Manpower Service Council, 1976. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - Manpower Services Council, 1977. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - Material for presentations, 1970-1973. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - Miner Relocation Project, Clincho Va. Proposal, 1972. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - State Planning and Community Affairs, Div. of, 1971-1976. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - State Planning and Community Affairs, Div. of, State Informational Directory, 1973. (Box 1)
  - Governor's Office - State Planning and Community Affairs, Div. of, Sub-State Regional Administration Study, 1975-1976. (Box 1)
  - Identification cards, 1971-1976. (Box 1)
  - Management Design, 1973-1974. (Box 1)
  - Management Design, 1974. (Box 1)
  - Management Development - Management Manpower Assessment Survey, 1972-1973. (Box 2)
  - Office Space, 1966-1977. (Box 2)
  - Office Space - Floor plans, undated. (Box 2)
  - Office Space - Leases, 1970-1974. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: General, 1970-1975. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: General, 1976-1977. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Committees, 1966-1973. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Committees, 1973-1976. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Committees - Publications, 1974-1976. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Financial, 1974-1977. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Meetings, 1971-1975. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Meetings, 1975-1977. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Personnel memos, 1971-1977. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Personnel memos - Standards of performance, 1974-1975. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Prospective, 1971. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Training, 1971-1977. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Lynchburg Region - Equipment and supplies, 1971-1977. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Lynchburg Region - Financial, 1974-1975. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Lynchburg Region - General, 1971-1977. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Lynchburg Region - Meetings, 1971-1977. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Lynchburg Region - Office space, 1970-1977. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Lynchburg Region - Personnel memos, 1971-1977. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Lynchburg Region - Reviews, Office Operations, 1972-1977. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Lynchburg Region - Training, 1972-1975. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - General, 1970-1973. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - General, 1974-1977. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - Equipment and supplies, 1970-1976. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - Financial, 1975. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - Goal setting program, 1972-1975. (Box 2)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - Memoranda ISY numbered, 1971-1972. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - Meetings, 1971-1975. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - Meetings, 1976-1977. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - Office space, 1970-1977. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - Personnel memoranda, 1971-1974. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - Personnel memoranda, 1975-1977. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - Reviews, Office Operations, 1972-1975. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - Reviews, Office Operations, 1975-1977. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - Training, 1971-1977. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Northern Virginia Region - Turnaround, 1976-1977. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Richmond Region - General, 1970-1974. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Richmond Region - General, 1975-1977. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Richmond Region - Equipment/Suppies, 1971-1977. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Richmond Region - Financial, 1973-1976. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Richmond Region - Meetings, 1971-1973. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Richmond Region - Meetings, 1974-1977. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Richmond Region - Personnel memoranda, 1971-1977. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Richmond Region - Reviews, Office Operations, 1972-1975. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Richmond Region - Reviews, Office Operations, 1976-1977. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Richmond Region - Training, 1971-1977. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Roanoke Region - General, 1970-1972. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Roanoke Region - General, 1973-1974. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Roanoke Region - General, 1975-1977. (Box 3)
  - Regional Offices: Roanoke Region - Equipment/Supplies, 1968-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Roanoke Region - Financial, 1974-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Roanoke Region - Meetings, 1971-1972. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Roanoke Region - Meetings, 1973-1976. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Roanoke Region - Office space, 1969-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Roanoke Region - Personnel memoranda, 1969-1974. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Roanoke Region - Personnel memoranda, 191975-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Roanoke Region - Reviews, Office Operations, 1971-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Roanoke Region - Training, 1971-1975. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Southwest Region - General, 1971-1976. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Southwest Region - Equipment/Supplies, 1971-1974. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Southwest Region - Financial, 1974-1976. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Southwest Region - Meetings, 1972-1976. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Southwest Region - Office space, 1971-1975. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Southwest Region - Personnel memoranda, 1971-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Southwest Region - Reviews, Office Operations, 1975-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Southwest Region - Training, 1973-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Tidewater Region - General, 1971-1975. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Tidewater Region - General, 1976-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Tidewater Region - Equipment/Supplies, 1970-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Tidewater Region - Financial, 1975. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Tidewater Region - Meetings, 1971-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Tidewater Region - Office space, 1963-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Tidewater Region - Personnel memoranda, 1971-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Tidewater Region - Reviews, Office operations, 1975-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Tidewater Region - Training, 1974-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Tidewater Region - Training needs for specialists, 1973-1975. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Valley Region - General, 1971-1978. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Valley Region - Equipment/Supplies, 1972-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Valley Region - Financial, 1974-1976. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Valley Region - Meetings, 1972-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Valley Region - Office space, 1970-1976. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Valley Region - Personnel memoranda, 1971-1977. (Box 4)
  - Regional Offices: Valley Region - Reviews, Office Operations, 1975-1977. (Box 5)
  - Regional Offices: Valley Region - Training, 1974-1977. (Box 5)
  - Travel, 1966-1974. (Box 5)
  - Travel, 1974-1977. (Box 5)
  - Travel - Gasoline purchases, 1966-1976. (Box 5)
  - Travel - State cars, 1960-1977. (Box 5)
  - Committees: Central Office/Regional Offices Teambuilding, 1973. (Box 5)
  - Committees: Local Administration Task Force, 1973. (Box 5)
  - Committees: Personnel Orientation and Development, 1970-1972. (Box 5)
  - Committees: Personnel Orientation and Development, 1973-1974. (Box 5)
  - Committees: Regional Policy Committee, 1974. (Box 5)
  - Committees: Transition Management, 1972-1974. (Box 5)
  - Committees: Transition Management - Draft introduction, 1973. (Box 5)
  - Committees: Transition Management - Meetings, 1972. (Box 5)
  - Committees: Transition Management - Training sessions, 1973. (Box 5)
  - Administrative reviews - Local/General, 1977-1978. (Box 5)
  - Budget allocation - Expenditure plan, 1976. (Box 5)
  - Caseload Standards, 1976-1978. (Box 5)
  - Commissioner's Office, 1976-1977. (Box 5)
  - Contracts/agreements - Cooperative/Local, 1976-1977. (Box 5)
  - Contracts/agreements - Other state agencies, 1976-1978. (Box 5)
  - Divisions - Administration, 1977-1978. (Box 5)
  - Divisions - Financial Services, 1977-1978. (Box 5)
  - Divisions - Support Enforcement, 1977-1978. (Box 5)
  - Emergency Services, 1973-1975. (Box 5)
  - Oaths of office - Local, 1977-1978. (Box 5)
  - Performance standards - Regional directors, 1977-1978. (Box 5)
  - Special Projects - Edgemeade, 1978. (Box 5)
  - Special Projects - FMC Plant (Fredericksburg), 19. (Box 5)
  - Special Projects - CETA Program, 1978. (Box 5)